Ashish Kumar Kanwar

E-mail: ashishthakur913@gmail.com | Phone: +1 514-546-3111

SUMMARY

I love building new things from scratch and that is what I had been doing at Zomato for over three years. Personally, I am a tinkerer (DIY crafts, remote cars, LEGO) and that has always made me believe that I can build anything I desire. I am very passionate about writing code and bringing life-changing products to life. Aspire to work on projects which spin me out of comfort zone to make me learn new things every day to feed my curiosity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Zomato

October 2015 — August 2018

Software Engineer

- ° Worked extensively on a fast-paced developing product having its presence in 23 countries, operating in 11 languages with a user base of 17 million with a small tech team of about 100 people.
- Worked on a product to detect real-time user location based on GPS and WiFi fingerprinting to provide location-based recommendations.
- o Made the photo-viewer for Zomato's website, the current live version, in react.js.
- Worked on Zomato's web platform which involved pushing new features live doing both front end and back end.
- Revamped whole website's UI/UX back in 2016.
- Worked on website optimization bringing down the page load times by about 0.5 seconds.
- Implemented Google's AMP (Accelerated Mobile Pages) for Zomato's mobile web. Got featured on Google's blog post for the same.
- o Implemented PWA (Progressive Web App) for Zomato's mobile web with a small team of five.
- Extensively worked on backend APIs for the mobile apps (IOS / Android).
- Made various internal tools for the ad sales team helping them derive more revenue.
- Hands-on experience with the build and deploy process of the web platform involving JS tools like grunt, gulp, webpack.
- Worked on Zomato's new product "Zomato Gold" contributing towards both tech and the product management.
- Worked on "Zomato Book" a table reservation platform as an ad-hoc developer for short duration.

Art Of Where, Montreal

October 2018 — Ongoing

Software Engineer

Maintaining and adding new features to the website and the backend which also manages entire manufacturing process. Most recent tasks was to split the monolith into microservices. Built an NFC chrome extension to enable login using tap cards.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PHP, Javascript, React JS with Redux, Java, Golang, Mysql, Redis, Cassandra, Elastic Search, Memcache, Infrastructure Automation

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

August 2011 — August 2015

Punjab Technical University

Currently pursuing Masters in CS from Concordia University, Montreal (2018 - 2020)

VOLUNTEER WORK

Robin Hood Army

Working with the organization, which helps restaurants distribute left over food to the poor people in need.